A networking model worth looking into is the
TCP model or Transmission Control Protocol
model.
Unlike the OSI model, which has seven layers,
the TCP model, also known as the TCP/IP model,
has four layers: the Network Access Layer,
the Internet Layer, the Transport Layer, and
the Application Layer.
From the top-down, the Application Layer performs
the duties of the Application, Presentation,
and Session Layers of the OSI model.
Thus, this layer is responsible for formatting
data and opening a session with a recipient
of the data.
The Transport Layer in the TCP model does
the same thing as the Transport Layer in the
OSI model, which is data segmentation.
The Internet Layer in the TCP model mirrors
the Network Layer in the OSI model.
This layer is responsible for getting data
into packets and addressing those packets.
Finally, the Network Access Layer in the TCP
model has the same duties as the Data Link
and Physical Layers in the OSI model.
That is to break the data down into frames,
add a physical address to the frames, break
the data down into bits, and get those bits
transferred over physical media from a source
to a destination.